我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
我让杀害母亲的凶手自食其果
I hunted down the man who killed my mother,
但我们的世界也因此出现了新的威胁
but in doing so, I opened up our world to new threats,
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
and I am the only one fast enough to stop them.
我叫闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
你来这里干什么
Why are you here?
因为我想跑得更快
Because I want to go faster,
而且只有你能教我
and you're the only one who can teach me.
你所需的一切都在这个驱动里
Everything you need is on this drive.
这意义很大  你关心着巴里
It means a lot, you looking after Barry.
我并不只是想保证巴里的安全
Barry's not the only person here I'm keeping safe.
我们找到了巴里的二重身
We found Barry's double,
我的二重身在哪儿
so where the hell am I?
回波
Reverb.
你不知道自己有多强大
You don't even know how powerful you are.
他叫亨特·佐勒蒙
His name was Hunter Zolomon.
我以为假如能在这个地球上
I thought that if I could find
找到我的二重身的话
my doppelganger on this Earth,
我可以用他的健康细胞
I could replace my damaged cells
替换我的受损细胞
with some of his healthy ones.
我一直震波看到极速
I've been vibing Zoom,
每次都是发生在我
and every time it's happened,
靠近那玩意儿的时候
I've been near that thing.
我看见杰伊了  他就是极速
I saw Jay. He's Zoom.
有时  年幼的我们会遇到些可怕的事
Sometimes terrible things happen to us when we're children.
十五年前
那些事会影响我们的人生
Things that can define who we become,
不论我们是否愿意
whether we want them to or not.
跑  巴里  快跑
Run, Barry, run!
有的人因此变得更强大
Some of us become stronger.
而照顾我  安慰我
The people who took me and helped me heal
陪我度过这一切的人
and move past everything that happened.
是他们造就了今天的我
They're responsible for who I've become today.
可我知道自己很幸运
But I know that I'm one of the lucky ones.
过来  巴里
Come on, Barry.
不是人人都能得到这种支持
Not everyone gets that kind of support.
要是没有这种支持  我将前途难料
Without it, I don't know where I would have ended up
人生难定
or what I could've become.
地球二  多年前
詹姆斯
James
你以为自己是谁
Who do you think you are?
你知道我在那里经历了什么吗
Do you know what I went through over there?
你知道我为你牺牲了什么吗
Do you know the sacrifices I made for you?
我为国征战数年  好不容易回来
I come back after years of fighting for this country
你就这样欢迎我回家吗
and this is my welcome home?
你以为自己能摆脱我吗
You think you can walk out on me?
我可是你的丈夫
I'm your husband!
你不是我的丈夫
You're not my husband.
我现在根本认不出你了
I don't know what you are right now.
我是英雄  艾希莉
I am a hero, Ashley.
不  你是个魔鬼
No. You're a monster.
跑  亨特  快跑
Run, Hunter, run.
站住  小子
Stay, boy!
没事的
It's okay.
过来
Come on.
求你  求你别这样
Please. Please don't do this.
-闭嘴  -不要  求你
- Shut up! - No, please.
不要
No.
睁大眼睛看好了  儿子
You're gonna want to see this, son.
不  詹姆斯
No, James!
No, James.
不
No!
孤儿院
名字
Name?
亨特·佐勒蒙
Hunter Zolomon.
父亲杀了母亲  孩子目睹了全程
Father killed the mother. Kid saw the whole thing.
有近亲吗
Next of kin?
亲人都不想收留他
No relatives wanted him.
他孤身一人
He is all alone.
跟我来
Follow me.
别慢吞吞的
And don't dawdle.
楔石城
好了  各位
Okay, you guys.
我到了  知道我的位置了吗
I'm here. You got my location?
你还好吗  不需要先热热身什么的吗
You're good? You don't need to, like, stretch or something?
不用  不用  我很好  我很好
No, no, no, I'm good, I'm good.
那我们就测试一下这个超光粒子增强器吧
Let's take this tachyon enhancer out for a test drive.
好的
All right.
太棒了  我感觉到了
Hoo, yeah. I feel that.
这是因为超光粒子增强器
That is the tachyon device
增强了你细胞里的神速力
powering up the Speed Force in your cells
就像快速充电电池似的
like a quick charge battery.
你感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
感觉不一样
Different.
看看你跑回来得花多长时间吧
Let's see how long it takes you to get back here.
听我命令
On my count.
三  二  一
Three, two, one.
跑
Go!
这玩意都让你达到巡航速度了
Dang, this thing got you cruising.
他平时能跑多快
How fast does he normally go?
没这么快
Not this fast.
比这差远了  他的生命体征怎么样
Not even close. Are his vitals okay?
都非常好
Yeah, they're perfect.
酷  这简直像是在胸前装了一座加油站
Cool. It's like having a pit-stop attached to your chest.
各位  我还能跑得更快
Guys, I can go faster.
跑啊
Do it.
我回来了
I'm back.
我跑了多长时间
What... how long was I gone?
这么说吧
Let's put it this way,
你甩了以前的记录好几条街
you just annihilated your old record.
是的  你比以前最快时还快了四倍
Yeah, you went four times faster than you have ever been.
四倍吗
Four times?
-那就... -那就和极速一样快了
- That's as... - Fast as Zoom.
实际上比他更快
Well, faster actually.
我们能不能把这玩意弄小一点
Do we think that we can get this thing smaller?
挺难看的
It kind of sucks.
如果你觉得难看  那就改吧
If it sucks, then, yeah.
好的  现在我们需要做的
All right, so now all we have to do
就是想出回去找极速的办法
is figure out how to get back to Zoom.
是的  不过有个小问题
Yes, just a minor issue.
我们把所有的缺口都关闭了
We closed all the breaches
而且也不知道要怎么重新打开它们
and have no idea how to reopen them.
不知道...  威尔斯
We don't... Wells?
我有个想法  艾伦
Yeah, I have an idea, Allen.
不如我们永远不要打开缺口
Let's keep the breaches closed forever.
忘记缺口  忘记极速
Forget about the breaches. Forget about Zoom.
等等  你之前不是已经想通了吗
Wait, I'm sorry, I thought that you were on board with this.
没有  我之前只是说帮你跑得更快
No. No. I said I would help you get faster.
我可没说我会帮你给那个男人
I did not say I would help you give the man
第二次绑架和折磨我的女儿的机会
who kidnapped my daughter and tortured her a chance to do it again.
我们不会让那种事发生的
Hey, we are not gonna let that happen.
你们不会让那种事发生
Oh, you're not gonna let that happen.
天呐  要是上一次我就知道该多好
Gosh, I wish I'd known that the first time.
你们不明白  极速他跟我们不一样
You don't understand. Zoom is different than us.
极速对任何东西都没有感情
Zoom is not tied to anything.
极速不关心任何人
Zoom does not care for anyone.
但我不一样
I do.
我的女儿还在这个地球上的某个地方
My daughter's out here on this Earth somewhere.
我得去找到她
I have to find her.
我们都有自己关心的人
We all have people that we care about.
极速会利用这点来对付我们的  相信我
Zoom will use that against us. Believe me.
或许我们不应该继续了
Maybe we should just leave it be.
不  不行  听我说
No, no. Look, no.
听着  我们不能不管另一个地球
Look, we're-- we're not turning our backs on another Earth.
我们不能让极速
We're not gonna let Zoom
逃避他该受的惩罚
get away with everything that he's done.
现在没有办法去另一个地球  艾伦
Right now, there is no way to another Earth, Allen.
就保持这样吧
Let's keep it that way.
我们一定要回到地球二上去
We're getting back to Earth-2.
无论他帮不帮忙
With or without his help.
开始干活吧
Let's go to work.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我们需要你的帮忙
We could use your help.
是的  我会帮的
Uh, yeah, I would.
只是我跟斯科特有个约会
It's just I have a date with Scott.
就是那个编辑吗
That's the editor?
是的  是的
Yeah, yeah.
很好啊  我很高兴你终于能
That's good. No, I'm glad that you're finding a way
忘记以前  向前看了
to move on without anything holding you back.
你应该幸福
You deserve that.
是啊  可如果没有你的支持我也做不到
Yeah, and well, I would have been able to do it without your support.
这对我很重要  所以
It means a lot to me, so...
-那自然  -谢谢
- Of course. - Thanks.
没事  不客气
Yes, for sure.
我说  如果你今晚前搞不定这个缺口问题
Well hey, I mean, if you don't get this breach problem fixed by tonight,
暂定我明晚过来帮忙可以吗
pencil me in for tomorrow?
可以这么安排
I can do that.
好的
Okay.
天呐  我太喜欢你在楔石城训练了
Man, I love it when you train in Keystone City.
你晚饭后想留下来吗
Hey, you sticking around after dinner?
我和沃利要看一级方程式锦标赛
Me and Wally are gonna watch Formula 1.
不  我不行
No, I can't.
我得回实验室
I got to get back to the lab.
我还在试着寻找回到地球二的方法
I'm still trying to find a way back to Earth-2.
你不能让威尔斯去操心吗
Can't you just stick Wells on it?
不行  他拒绝了
No, he refused.
他不想让我或是任何人再打开缺口
Doesn't want me or anybody opening the breaches again.
好吧  我不敢相信自己要这么说
Well, I can't believe I'm saying this
对这样一个被我开枪打过
about a man I shot at--
还在他脸上打了几拳的人
and punched in the face,
但我觉得你应该听他的
but I think you should listen to him.
为什么
Why?
巴里  我一想到你要回地球二
Barry, it worries the hell out of me
我就担心得要死
the thought that you want to go back to Earth-2.
我现在更快了  前所未有的快
I'm faster now. I'm faster than I've ever been.
我比极速还快
I'm faster than Zoom.
我可以打倒他的
I can take him down.
我想说是
All I'm saying is,
你已经虎口脱险过一次了
you already escaped the hornet's nest once.
为什么还要再去冒险
Why go back and kick it again?
沃利
Wally!
这儿有大老远从楔石城弄来的一些披萨
We got some pizza here all the way from Keystone City.
希望你们不介意我把衣服带来洗
Hope it's cool I brought my laundry over.
当然不  巴里上大学的时候
Of course. Barry used to do his laundry here
总是把他的衣服带来这里洗
all the time when he was in college.
那是因为寝室里的那些洗衣机
That's cause those machines in the dorm
总是吞你的硬币  对吗
always eat your quarters, right?
其实  我已经不住在学校里了
Actually, I'm not, uh, living on campus anymore.
什么  从什么时候开始的
What? Since when?
从食宿费变得比我想像中的贵很多开始
Since room and board became way more expensive than I thought.
小子  我可以帮你解决这个问题
Man, I can help you out with that.
我猜你在付完你母亲的医疗费后
I figured your money must be tight
手头可能会有点紧张
after paying all your mother's medical bills.
食宿费贵了多少
How much more is it?
不  没事的
No, it's, uh, it's cool.
别这样  沃利  让我帮你吧
Come on, Wally, let me help you out.
而且我车库里还有个迷你冰箱
Plus I got that mini-fridge in the garage.
你也可以拿去用  如果你想的话
You can use that, too, if you want.
乔  我没事  真的
Joe, I'm good. Really.
好吧
All right.
让我赶紧把这些放进去
Uh, let me just put these in real quick.
天呐  我有时候真是搞不懂那孩子
Man, I can't figure that kid out sometimes.
我在想他的二重身会不会也这么复杂
I wonder if his doppelganger's that complicated.
有办法了吗
Um, any ideas?
我们目前想到的最好的方案
Well, the best plan we've come up with so far
就是把一枚核弹头发射到城市电网旁边
is to set off a nuclear warhead next to the city's electrical grid,
所以...
so...
我们可不能那么做
We're not gonna do that.
不过我好像想到了一个方法
I think I thought of something though.
告诉我你所知道的
Tell me everything that you know
关于西斯科的二重身的一切
about Cisco's doppelganger.
回波
Reverb.
回波在你的地球上的超能力是什么
What were Reverb's powers on your Earth?
他能利用地球之间的多维度能量
He could tap into the multi-dimensional energies between Earths.
他可以看透多个维度
He could see through dimensions.
找到穿越者  就像拉蒙一样
Find breachers, like Ramon.
我们看见回波能做的不止这些  对吗
I mean, we--we saw Reverb do more than that though, right?
我们看见他从手中发出振动脉冲
I mean, we saw him shoot vibrational bursts out of his hands.
让人很痛的那种
Really painful ones.
你想表达什么
What do you mean?
我是说  回波有某种能力
I-I mean, Reverb had the ability to somehow
可以操控多维度能量
manipulate that multi-dimensional energy.
你想说什么  艾伦
What's your point, Allen?
我想说的是
My point is...
如果他的能力
if his powers
和那种联系起多宇宙的能量相关联
are linked to the energy that ties together the multi-verse--
如果他能操控它
if he can manipulate it--
那么他就能在任何地球上打开缺口
then he can open a breach to any Earth he wants.
没错  如果回波可以做到
Exactly. And if Reverb could do it...
我也可以
I could do it too.
西斯科  我想回到地球二就靠你了
Cisco, I think the way back to Earth-2 is you.
我什么都没感觉到
I got nothing.
再试一次  好吗
Try again, okay?
巴里  如果他做不到
Barry, what if he can't do it
是因为他觉得自己做不到呢
because he thinks he can't do it?
他可以做到的  你可以做到
He can do it though. You can do it.
你  会成功的  好吗
You--it's gonna work, okay.
也许只是我们地方选的不对
Maybe we're just not in the right place.
或者是因为你选错人了  好吗
Or maybe I'm just not the right man for the job. Right?
我们走
Let's go.
西斯科
Cisco.
抱歉  巴里
I'm sorry, Barry.
会成功的
It's gonna work.
警探
Detective,
我有问题问你
I need to ask you--
还有别人在啊
Oh, you've got company.
没事  反正我也要去学习了
No, it's, uh, cool. I should be studying anyway.
你知道你有点像那个人...
Do you know you kind of look like that guy--
我不是他
I'm not him.
好吧
Okay.
再见  乔
Later, Joe.
谢谢你
Thank you. Look, um,
很抱歉我不请自来了  只是...
I apologize for dropping by unannounced. I just...
找我女儿的事有进展了吗
have you had any luck locating my daughter?
还没  但全区所有部门
Not yet, but I circulated her picture
都有她的照片
through every department in the region.
我还找了楔石城的几个朋友
And I reached out to some friends in Keystone.
她很聪明
She's smart.
她懂得如何隐藏
She's gonna know how to stay hidden.
-她... -我们会找到她的
- She's... - We'll find her.
好吧
Right.
还有一件事  警探
There's another thing also, Detective.
一个小忙
A favor.
我想让你劝巴里放弃
I would ask you to talk Barry out
重新打开通往地球二的缺口
of reopening the breaches to my Earth.
我做不到
Ah, I can't do that.
不
No.
你没办法让他改变想法吗
You can't find a way to change his mind
考虑下我们的孩子
for both our children's sakes?
听着
Look,
我和你一样觉得这事很蠢
I think it's just as dumb as you do.
但我很早就知道  一旦巴里
But I learned a long time ago that I can't talk Barry
下定决心  就没有商量余地了
out of anything once he sets his mind to it.
极速恐吓着另一个世界  你的世界
Zoom is terrorizing this other world--your world.
他不会放任不管
He can't let it go.
但是  你不如帮我个忙吧
But look, why don't you do me a favor?
和巴里一起去
Go with Barry.
帮助他
Help him.
Help him?
我为什么要帮他
Why would I do that?
因为有你在  他打败极速的机会
'Cause he's got a much better chance of defeating Zoom
就会更大
if you're involved.
这个区域的超维能量
This area has the highest levels
残存量最多
of residual trans-dimensional energy.
应该能打开这里之前的缺口
Should be able to open the breach that used to be here.
就在这  就是这里了
It's right here. This is it.
真的  这简直就是《心灵点滴》噩梦版
For real? In this Patch Adams nightmare right here?
讲述穿着滑稽以此逗病人开心的精神病医生的故事
是啊  大爱
Yeah. Love it.
好吧
All right.
兄弟  如果这还是没用
Look, dude, if this doesn't work,
我就不再让你做这种事了  好吗
I'll stop asking you to do this, all right?
好的
Okay.
怎么
What?
我做不到
I can't do it.
没错
That's right.
你做不到
You can't.
你来做什么  你说过...
What are you doing here? You said--
我知道我说过什么
I know what I said.
但你不会停手的  对不对
But you're not gonna stop, are you?
不会
No.
好  巴里·艾伦  我会尽最大努力
Okay, Barry Allen, then I'm gonna do what I can
保住你的小命
to make sure you don't get killed.
我重调了这东西
I recalibrated these
将电磁频率与这个地球匹配
to the electromagnetic frequency of this Earth.
应该能帮你获得
It should help you access enough
足够多的超维能量
of the trans-dimensional energy
进行操控
to manipulate it.
就像回波一样
Just like Reverb.
我只要化上他那种男士眼影
All I'm missing is the guyliner
就和他一样了
and the transformation's complete.
试试看吧
Take 'em out for a spin.
起作用了
It's working.
继续  西斯科  继续
Keep coming, Cisco. Keep coming.
起作用了
It's working.
怎么了  你刚刚做到了
Hey, what--what happened? You were doing it.
不  不  不  我做不到
No, no, no, no. I-I can't do this.
-什么  -别
- What? - Don't.
求你们了  别让我做这个
Please, don't ask me to do this.
求你们了
Please.
进展如何
What do we got?
这是超光速粒子吸收增强器的改进版本
It's your tachyon absorption enhancer upgrade.
这之前会夺走你的速度  现在改进成
Retrofitted from when it was used to steal your speed,
可为你提供更多的速度
to now give you more of it.
就快完成了
Almost done.
这太不可思议了  谢谢
That's amazing. Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
西斯科回来了吗  有人见到他了没
Is Cisco back yet? Have we seen him?
-我没看到他  -去他工作室看看
- I haven't seen him. - Check his workshop.
好的
Yeah, all right.
我们顺路看看有什么要帮忙的
We just came by to see if you guys needed some help.
当然
Uh, sure.
-需要  -多点帮手总是好的
- Yeah. - We can always use an extra set of hands.
你来医疗区帮我吧
Do you want to help me in the med bay?
好的
Yeah.
所以这个
So this-- -
沃利的事...
This whole Wally thing...
他不让我帮他
He won't let me help him.
可能是因为
It's probably 'cause you're not
你没帮对忙
offering the right kind of help.
沃利不想要你帮他付房租
Wally doesn't want your help paying for a place to live.
他希望你能让他搬去你家住
He wants you to offer him a place to live.
那他为什么不直说
Why didn't he just say that?
我不知道
I don't know.
所以他想和我们一起住吗
So he does want to live in our house?
对啊
Yeah, man.
听着  沃利之前从来没和父亲一起住过
Look, Wally's never lived with his father before.
相信我  这事可意义重大
And trust me, that is a big deal.
那你不会介意吗
And you're good with it?
我是说  你知道的
I mean, you know,
一直都是我和你一起住  我很喜欢
it's been you and me for so long, and I love that,
但沃利搬来一起住也没关系
but having Wally around would be cool too.
只是楔石城的披萨
Just we won't get to have
就得再分一点出去了
as much pizza from Keystone.
对  这倒有点不爽  抱歉
Yeah, it kind of sucks. I'm sorry.
你得习惯这样的生活了
Have to get used to that.
他们真的有种特殊的羁绊  对吗
They really have a special bond, don't they?
对  肯定有
Yeah, they sure do.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我也不知道怎么了
I don't know what I am.
昨晚  我本该去赴一场约会的
Last night, I was supposed to go on a date.
艾迪死后  我第一次正式约会
My first real date since Eddie died,
但在最后一刻  我还是没去
but at the last second, I just--I couldn't do it.
是因为艾迪还是巴里
Is it because of Eddie or because of Barry?
我注意到了你最近看他的眼神
I've noticed the way you've been looking at him recently.
有那么明显吗
Is it that obvious?
只是咱俩同病相怜
Only to a woman who's been through the same thing.
一切似乎都在告诉我
Everything seems to be telling me
我和巴里注定要在一起
that Barry and I are meant to be together.
我是说  在地球二上我们结婚了
I mean, on Earth-2 we're married.
在未来  我们也应该会结婚
In the future, we're supposedly married.
而现在我终于准备好向前看了
And now that I'm finally ready to move on,
我只是在想巴里是那个对的人吗
I just wonder if that should be with Barry.
一切似乎都在指向那个方向
Everything seems to be pointing in that direction.
你相信命运吗  凯特琳
Do you believe in destiny, Caitlin?
你或许该信
Maybe for you.
有人吗
Hello?
乔
Joe?
沃利  我在楼上
Wally, I'm up here.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
还没收拾好
It's not done yet.
你可以按你的喜好来装饰这里
I mean, you can decorate it how you like.
打造你的个人空间
Make it your own.
等等  乔  这是怎么回事
Whoa, wait, Joe. What is this?
沃利  原谅我
Wally, forgive me.
巴里和爱瑞丝去上大学的时候
When Barry and Iris went to college,
他们恨不得赶快走
they couldn't get away fast enough.
他们不想再呆在他们的老爸身边
They wanted nothing to do with their old man.
我居然一直没想到
It didn't even occur to me
你可能不是这么觉得的
that you might feel differently.
太丢脸了  有了巴里的帮助我才认清这一点
It's embarrassing, but it took Barry to help me see that.
所以如果你还没找到住的地方
So, if you still haven't found a place to live,
就住在这里吧
live here.
我是说  你想要的话就是你的了
I mean, it's yours if you want to.
你是认真的吗
You're serious?
我可不会给你洗衣服
I'm not gonna do your laundry.
我也不帮你洗盘子
And I'm not washing dishes after you.
而且每天早上走之前你要
And this bed is going to be made every morning
整理好床铺
before you leave.
而且冰箱里也不会存啤酒
And there will be no beer in that fridge,
但这一切都可以是你的
but yeah, it's yours.
我什么时候能搬进来
When can I move in?
你想什么时候都可以
Whenever you want.
好的
All right.
谢了  老爸
Thanks, dad.
哥们
Hey, man.
听着
Look, um...
我知道那种感受
I know what it's like...
极速进入你的思想
Zoom, getting in your head,
会有多恐怖
how scary that can be.
不是极速
It's not Zoom.
是我
It's me.
你说是你是什么意思
What do you mean it's you?
感觉就好像现在我是安纳金·天行者
It's like right now I'm Anakin Skywalker.
体内有迷地原虫
I got the midi-chlorians.
我含有一些物质
I've got the goods.
我体内的原力很强大
The force is strong with me.
这就是我能感受到的
That is something I can feel.
但如果我开始打开通往其他世界的缺口
But if I start opening breaches into other worlds,
做所有回波曾经做的事情  那么
doing all this other crazy stuff Reverb was doing, then...
如果我会因为这个成为维德呢
what if this is how I become Vader?
哥们  你永远也不会变成维德的
Dude, you're never going to become Vader.
你怎么知道  这正是回波的遭遇
You don't know that. That is what happened to Reverb.
他学习了如何运用他的能力
He learned how to use his abilities,
当他感受到了那个
and when he felt that,
当他感受到了力量
when he felt that power,
他屈服了
he succumbed...
向黑暗屈服
to the dark side.
听着  我理解你  真的
Look, I get it. I-I really do.
每当我学到了新的能力
Every time I've learned a new ability,
我都很害怕它对我来说意味着什么
I've been terrified about what it might mean for me.
它会对我有什么影响  你知道吗
What it could do to me, you know?
但你一直在我身边
But you were there with me
无论是当我学习如何在水上奔跑时
when I learned how to run on water,
还是我跑上一座建筑物时
when I ran up a building,
或者穿越时间的时候
or traveled through time.
我也会陪着你
Just like I'm gonna be there
走过你的每一步
every step of the way with you.
你有着回波从来不曾拥有的东西
You got something that Reverb never had,
那就是凯特琳  乔
and that's Caitlin and Joe
爱瑞斯  威尔斯  还有我
and Iris and Wells and me.
这些会照顾你的朋友
Friends who are gonna look out for you.
而且我们不仅是朋友
And we're more than just friends.
我们是你的家人
We're your family.
所以  你觉得怎么样
So what do you say?
准备好戴上那些东西
Ready to put those things on again,
再来一遍了吗
and go another round?
我们开始吧
Let's do it.
好的
All right.
已经弄好了
You're all set.
他不会发现这东西在那里
He won't even know it's there.
也不知道是谁说了美观并不重要
'Cause whoever said aesthetics aren't important.
反正不是我
Not me.
我们走
Let's go.
凯特琳  我知道这对你来说很不容易
Hey, Cait, I know how hard this is gonna be for you,
但我们得阻止他
but we have to stop him.
我知道  而且我也想支持你们
I know, and I want to be supportive.
我只是  我无法面对杰伊
I just-- I can't face Jay.
不管他真名叫什么
Or whatever his real name is.
这是什么意思
What does that mean?
你还记得
Well, you remember
我当时在找他的二重身  对吗
when I was looking for his doppelganger, right?
记得  你找不到他的二重身
Yeah. And you couldn't find him.
因为这个地球上没有杰伊·加里克
Because there is no Jay Garrick on this Earth.
他的二重身叫亨特·佐勒蒙
His doppelganger's name is Hunter Zolomon.
亨特·佐勒蒙
Hunter Zolomon?
你确定吗
Are you sure?
确定  怎么了
Yeah, why?
因为在我的地球上
Well, because on my Earth,
亨特·佐勒蒙被宣判为连环杀手
Hunter Zolomon was a convicted serial killer.
《中城新闻图报》
臭名昭著的连环杀手落入法网
那是杰伊吗
That's Jay?
不  那是亨特
No, that is Hunter.
亨特·佐勒蒙最后一张公开的照片
Last public photo of Hunter Zolomon.
我立刻就认出了
Instantly recognizable.
而来自我地球的人  在我的地球上
And people from my Earth-- on my Earth,
连环杀手不常见
serial killers are an anomaly,
所以很多媒体都关注这件事
so a lot of media attention to this.
连播客都报道过
There was a podcast.
在亨特十一岁时  他父亲杀死了他母亲
When Hunter was 11, his father killed his mother
就在他面前
right in front of him.
父亲被送进了监狱
Father sent to prison,
而亨特在寄养中心长大
Hunter grew up in the foster care system.
多年后  他被判犯下了23项谋杀罪
Years later he was convicted on 23 counts of murder.
23项  这简直是汉尼拔·莱克特的级别
23? That's, like, some real Hannibal Lecter type level.
审判之后  亨特被送到
After the trial, Hunter was sent
圣佩雷斯精神病院做精神病犯罪治疗
to the Saint Perez Mental Asylum for the Criminally Insane...
每日做电击疗法
given daily electroshock therapy.
治愈了他杀人的冲动  然后渐渐消退
Cure him of his urges and then faded from view.
直到那晚你的粒子加速器爆炸
Until the night your particle accelerator exploded.
是的  暗物质渗入了精神病院
That's right. The dark matter crept into the mental asylum.
我还以为
I had thought...
让爆炸发生在地下会减少接触率
piping the explosion underground would limit exposure.
我错了
I was wrong.
结果却弄出了一个无敌怪物
All it did was create an unstoppable monster.
《中城新闻图报》
臭名昭著的连环杀手落入法网
亨特·佐勒蒙
他不是无敌的
He's not unstoppable.
杰伊不知道我们已经知晓了他的身份
Jay doesn't know that we know who he really is.
他认为他的过去无人知晓
He thinks that his past is a secret.
然后呢
So?
我想我有办法阻止他
I think I have an idea of how we can stop him.
你肯定杰伊进不来吗
Are you sure Jay can't get in here?
相当肯定  但是以防万一
Pretty sure, but just in case.
这个要怎么用
How do you use this?
好吧  你要先瞄准
All right, so you aim it,
-然后扣下扳机  -聪明
- and then you pull the trigger. - Smart ass.
巴里和西斯科已经就位
Barry and Cisco are in position.
希望这玩意能起作用
Let's hope this thing works.
-准备好了吗  -准备好了
- You ready, buddy? - Yeah.
你们总是相信我
You've always believed in me.
-谢谢  -你可以的
- Thank you. - You got this.
回波的二重身
Reverb's doppelganger
已经增强了他的能量
has increased his powers.
仇恨是强大的刺激因素
Hatred is a strong motivator.
重新打开缺口的做法很不明智
You were unwise to reopen the breach.
我不会再让你恐吓另一个世界
I'm not gonna let you terrorize another world anymore.
你没有速度
Without your speed,
就没法阻止我
you won't be able to stop me.
走着瞧
Let's see.
极速正在向巴里逼近
Zoom's gaining on Barry.
他抓不到他的
He can't catch him.
最好抓不到
He better not.
-好险  -太险了
- That was close. - Too close.
超光速机起效了
The tachyon device is working.
他们要来了
Here they come.
他们进了大楼
They're here.
你的速度变快了
Ah, you've gotten faster.
好极了  有更多的速度供我取走
Good. There'll be more for me to take.
你想要我的速度吗
You want my speed?
来抓我吧
Catch me.
睁大眼睛看好了  儿子
You're gonna want to see this, son.
-抓住他  巴里  -成功了
- Get him, Barry. - It's working.
不
No!
你怎么知道我的身份
How did you figure out who I was?
你犯了一个错
You made a mistake.
你把你二重身的名字告诉了凯特琳
You told Caitlin who your doppelganger was.
我必须想办法接近她  阻止她治愈我
I had to do something to get her to stop trying to fix me.
她很聪明
She's a smart girl.
那你怎么知道我极速
And that I was Zoom?
终极速度-9
The Velocity-9.
当你跑到一定速度时
When you run fast enough,
极速者的闪电就会变成蓝色
it turns a speedster's lightning blue.
我们本来可以帮你
We would have helped you.
本来可以想办法救你的
We would have done anything we could to save your life.
无法全部治愈
Not everything.
凯特琳已经找到了治愈方法
Caitlin found you a cure.
那只是临时的
A temporary one!
我快死了  巴里
I'm dying, Barry!
只有一样东西能提供我所需
There's only one thing that can get me what I need.
你就一点都不在乎
And you just don't care
为了得到它要死多少人吗
how many lives you destroy trying to get it?
不在乎你要杀多少人
How many people you kill?
对  我不在乎
No, I don't!
我早就什么都不在乎了
That feeling was taken from me a long time ago.
我们俩并没有多大区别
We're not so different, you know.
年幼时那些遭遇
What happened to us when we were kids.
你原本也可能会变成我这样
You could have just as easily become me.
不
No.
我永远不会变成你那样
I'd never become like you.
我得说...
I got to say...
拿我父母来制约我  这招挺厉害
that was smart using my parents against me.
家庭  就是软肋
Oh, family. Such a weakness.
不是人人都会这样想
Not for all of us.
你错就错在这里
Well, that's where you're wrong.
是时候拿到我想要的东西了
It's time I get what I came for.
从我这你什么也得不到
You're not getting anything from me.
你再也得不到任何人的任何东西
You're not getting anything from anybody ever again.
在任何一个地球上
On any Earth.
你锁不住黑暗
You can't lock up the darkness.
你说什么
What did you just say?
你锁不住黑暗
You can't lock up the darkness.
不
No!
-他刚就在那  -我知道
- He was right there. - I know.
我们都已经抓到他了
I mean, we had him.
都已经抓到了  怎么会让他跑了
We had him. I can't believe it.
-沃利  -这边
- Wally? - Up here!
用你的速度交换沃利
这是哪里
Where are we?
我们在哪
救命  谁来救救我
Help! Somebody please help!
现在只有一个人能救你
There's only one person who can help you now.
闪电侠
The Flash.
闪电侠  他怎么会来救我
The Flash? Why would he help me?
他都不认识我
He doesn't even know who I am.
他在乎的人...
Someone he cares about...
在乎你
cares about you.
爸爸
Dad?
Dad.
喝咖啡吗
Coffee?
我们会把他救回来的
We're gonna get him back.
我们能不能利用震波阻止极速
What if we could stop Zoom through a vibe somehow?
我们可以把护目镜制成武器...
We could weaponize the goggles...
时间不够的  拉蒙
Not enough time to weaponize, Ramon.
好吧  那能不能改装脉冲步枪
Okay, what if we modify the pulse rifle
让它发射低频电磁辐射
to emit a low-level EMF?
我们现在没有器材来改装
We don't have the equipment to modify the pulse rifles now.
那我们再来一次突击营救
Then we do another snatch and grab mission.
等我们登上悬崖  极速可能早就...
By the time we scale those cliffs, Zoom could already--
让我安静会
I need a minute.
巴里  我知道你...
Barry, I know you...
不能把你的速度给那怪物  但...
can't give up your speed to that monster, but...
我也知道我想救回我儿子
I also know that I want to get my son back,
我不知道怎么办
and I don't know what to do.
我知道
I do.
沃利他...  他是家里的一份子
Wally, he's... he's part of the family.
他是...我们家的...
He's... he's a part of...
一份子
our family.
我们会不惜一切代价
And we do whatever we have to
护我们在乎的人周全
to keep the ones we care about safe.
不行  你...
No, you...
不能把你的速度给他
you can't give up your speed.
决定权在我
That's not your decision.
这是唯一的办法  乔
This is the only way, Joe.
巴里  你确定要这样做吗
Barry, are you sure?
我确定
I'm sure.
我都不确定他能不能听到我
I mean, we don't even know if he'll be able to hear me.
他会听到的
He'll hear you.
我看到他了
I see him.
沃利还活着
Wally's alive.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
你看到杰伊了吗
Do you see Jay?
看到了
I see him.
他能感觉到我
He can sense me.
杰伊
Jay?
震波
Vibe.
他同意了
He'll do it.
巴里会把速度给你
Barry will give you his speed.
宝贝
Babe.
-爸爸  -沃利  坚持住
- Dad? - Wally, hold on.
放了他
Let him go.
我们谈好条件了
We had a deal.
用我的速度换沃利的命
My speed for Wally's life.
交出他来  速度给你
Hand him over, and it's yours.
-你没事吧  -没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
你得赶快离开这里
You need to get out of here now.
-好的  -快走
- Okay. - Go fast.
-西斯科  -我们走
- Cisco! - Let's go.
我们来做个了断吧
Let's get this over with.
一开始  我就是用这个
This thing is how I stole
偷走了闪电侠的速度
the Flash's speed the first time.
现在他只需要奔跑
Now all he needs to do is run,
把神速力注入这个瓶子里
and his Speed Force will transfer into this vial.
但只能在我的校验下
but only as long as I calibrate it.
开始吧
Get to work.
威尔斯
Wells.
有一天
One day...
我会把你这张贱脸打开花
I'm gonna knock that smug expression clean off your face.
这就是你一直以来的计划吗
So this was your plan all along, huh?
从天空裂开展露另一个世界时起
Ever since the skies parted and showed me another world...
以及另一个极速者
with another speedster.
看到你后  我就来了
Once I saw you, I came here,
我明白了自己该做什么
I figured out what I had to do.
你为什么还活着
How are you still alive?
我们看到你死了
We saw you die.
没错
You did.
所以怎么回事  是极速幻象吗
So what was that? A speed mirage?
极速幻象
Speed mirage?
不是的  连我都没那么快
Uh, no. Even I'm not that fast.
我知道自己不能同时出现在两个地球
I knew that I couldn't be on two Earths at the same time,
所以我穿越到过去
so I went back in time and, uh,
看到了另一个版本的自己
met another version of myself.
你的"时间残余"  就像逆闪电那样
Your time remnant. Like the Reverse-Flash.
我还知道让巴里变快的唯一方法
I also knew that the only way to make Barry become faster
就是让你们见证老朋友杰伊的死
was if you all witnessed your old pal Jay die.
你什么时候决定那样做的
When did you decide to do that?
当你们关闭所有缺口  去到地球二时
Oh, once you closed all the breaches, went to Earth-2.
相信我  说服我的时间残余
Believe me, getting my time remnant
让我杀掉他  可挺费劲的呢
to agree to me murdering him took a bit of convincing.
但当他发现  我计划的高明之处时
But once he saw the... well, the genius in my plan,
他全然同意了
he was all for it.
那个戴铁面具的人是谁
Who's the man in the iron mask?
我告诉你你会惊呆的
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
为何装模作样
Why the charade?
穿着闪电侠的衣服到处跑
Running around dressed like the Flash?
给人们以希望  警探
To give people hope, Detective.
希望
Hope?
那样我就可以再次夺走它们
So I could rip it away from them.
假装自己是
It's so fun
英雄  是一件很有意思的事
pretending to be a hero.
你不是英雄
You are no hero.
你只是个魔鬼
You're nothing but a monster.
你是个魔鬼
You're a monster.
不
No!
-巴里  -没事的  乔
- Barry. - It's all right, Joe.
他慢下来了
He's slowing down.
神速力在脱离他
The Speed Force is leaving his body.
他又要变成普通人了
He's becoming human again.
神速力输送 100%
巴里  你没事吧
Barry, are you okay?
我没事  我没事
I'm okay. I'm okay.
-谢了  闪电侠  -杰伊  住手
- Thank you, Flash. - Jay, stop.
不要这样
Please.
如果你对我说过的话是真心的
If anything you ever said to me was true,
如果我们共同有过的感情是真的
or anything we ever shared was real,
那请你放了他吧  求你了
then please just let him go. Please.
我知道你心里是在乎过我的
I know some piece of you did care for me,
如果你还有一点人性尚存
so if you have any humanity left,
那求求你  放了他
then please, let him go.
凯特琳
Caitlin!